Artem Shar

Frontend Web-Developer

Email: artem.ude@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/artemshar

Telegram: t.me/artemshar
Site: artemshar.space

GitHub: github.com/artemshar

Summary

I develop Frontend / Web Applications for 6+ years. I strive to create stable and working interfaces, scalable, accessible components, and implement the designers ideas.

Most of all I use: React, TypeScript/JavaScript, Redux, SCSS/CSS, Storybook. But also I have experience with Vue.js. I used a lot of JavaScript tools, UI Libraries like Ant.Design or Semantic UI, SaaS services for Backend, CMS, and other web-technologies which I can say "I can work with them".

Worked in international companies. I have worked on key features, which were sent to product release, and they're still working. I have single work experience & team works with other developers, designers, project and product managers, OA.

Work experience (2016-2022)

Companies and projects in which I worked as a Front-end, Web Developer, UI developer, Design Developer.

Oken Tech, 2022

Chrome Extension, Web Sockets, React, CSS/SCSS, TypeScript, JavaScript

- Improving UI of Chrome Extension
- Code refactoring
- Worked on a new feature

Clay Global, 2021 - 2022

React, CSS/SCSS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Storybook

- Creating reusable scalable interactive React components based on mockups from designers
- Develop new corporate website for <u>the Reyes Holdings</u> (React, TypeScript, Next.js, CSS)
- Preparing <u>the Reyes Holdings</u> website for obtaining WCAG certificate
- Writing documentation for the internal library of utilities and components with Storybook

Unicorn Platform, 2020 - 2021

React, CSS/SCSS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Axios, Redux, AntDesign, Python, Django, Google Sheets API, UX/UI, jQuery

- Develop blogs functionality: posts editor, websites dashboard, settings
- Develop integration forms with Google Sheets API
- Develop templates functionality
- Support features, communicating with clients
- Bug fixing

Emergn (ex. Return on Intelligence), 2018 - 2020

HTML, CSS/SCSS. CSS-in-JS, Next.js, JavaScript, React, Vue, Grunt, jQuery

- o Development web interfaces for Hotelplan, Mercer, Emergn
- Architectural solutions for splitting interface elements into components, UX, DX, creating reusable components based on a design, brand book, or without mocup

- Simplification of development processes, cutting off unnecessary steps to speed up the process and reduce the number of bugs and the complexity of implementing the UI code
- Support for the development team in styling, design, UX
- Support and refactoring outdated code
- Exchange of knowledge within the team about UX, design, interface, development processes
- \circ Communications & clarification of requirements from customers in English
- Work in close contact with UX designers, analysts, project managers, backend developers, testers

Hotelplan, Migros-Ferien, Mercer

Hotelplan Holding AG:

- Develop a new travel project
- Bugfixes & New features in projects:
 - o Hotelplan
 - o Powderfinder
 - o <u>Migros-Ferien</u>

Mercer (Marsh & McLennan):

 Refactoring UI of a financial and analytical product from Flash to Vue.js

Internal Emergn Projects

- Consultancy Capability Assessment Tool (React SPA, MobX, Node.js)
- Customize design of SharePoint plugins and extensions
 (Org chart, MS Teams API) to the internal corporate site
- UI support to the internal corporate management system (.NET App)

Freelance (Game Dev startup), 2017 - 2018

CSS-animations, JavaScript, jQuery, Pixi.js, Node.js & Telegram API Basically, working with a startup in game dev in browser

- Developing interfaces for a Web Game project, using Canvas, Pixi.js, JS / CSS / HTML
- \circ $\,$ Inventing and realization animations, UX / UI to rich visualization of the game
- Mapping audio, graphics, and behavior in the interface with logic of the web-game
- Creating the chatbot with Telegram & Google Sheets to managing project team size about 10 people

- Managing graphics resources
- Writing documentation
- Improving and bug fixing UI / UX for projects, like shop, personal blog, site of web-studio

Grand Capital, 2016 - 2017

HTML, CSS, Gulp, Email-dev, Django

- Making marketing web-pages and implementation in the Web App on Django
- Improving UI / UX of main marketing site
- Creating email-templates to newsletters
- Working on a new trading web terminal

Education

- 2014 2017, Bachelor of "Business Informatics", Saint-Petersburg State Institute of Technology.
- 2010 2014, Specialist in "Audiovisual technology", College of Saint-Petersburg state university of Film and Television.

Additional experience in media and music

- \bigstar 2013 2015 Cinema projectionist and technical specialist in the large cinema.
- ★ 2009 2013 Active music production experience in electronic music. FL-Studio, VST, recording, sampling.

Contacts

o E-mail: artem.ude@gmail.com

o LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/artemshar

○ Telegram - <u>t.me/artemshar</u>

Site: <u>artemshar.space</u>

GitHub: github.com/artemshar